<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Juan Antonio Personal Website</title><link>https://www.antonoriza.com/</link><description>This is my cool site</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>hi@antonoriza.com (Juan Antonio Oriza Armas)</managingEditor><webMaster>hi@antonoriza.com (Juan Antonio Oriza Armas)</webMaster><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.antonoriza.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Exploring Economics: The purpose of economics</title><link>https://www.antonoriza.com/exploring-economics-the-purpose-of-economics/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Juan Antonio Oriza Armas</author><guid>https://www.antonoriza.com/exploring-economics-the-purpose-of-economics/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Shortly after I finished High school, I had decided to take 1 year to focus entirely on my entrepreneurial journey before university. I was lucky to be participating in a really good French incubator program led by two great economists in Mexico City. My interactions with them made me ask myself if I wanted to follow the engineering or the economics path.</p>
<p>I clearly choosed the engineering path after evaluating how my strengths and situation at that time could optimize to generate the most impact in my goals. Now the scope of my goals has grown, and thus the knowledge that I need to complete them too. Hopefully, a lot of the needed knowledge seems to hold on to &ldquo;economics&rdquo;.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>The tech stack powering this website</title><link>https://www.antonoriza.com/tech-stack-powering-this-website/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Juan Antonio Oriza Armas</author><guid>https://www.antonoriza.com/tech-stack-powering-this-website/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Hey there! If you know me through my side job related to building websites, you might assume this website is built with WordPress. But nope!</p>
<p>On my journey to becoming a writer, I wanted to learn something new (WordPress had become too easy for me) and experience the magical feeling that comes with learning and creating something new.</p>
<p>To be honest, my hacker mind initially thought, &ldquo;Let&rsquo;s build a blog from scratch using an esoteric programming language, create a solid framework, release it as open source to the public, and finally, build the blog on top of it.&rdquo;</p>]]></description></item><item><title>About Incremental and Disruptive innovations</title><link>https://www.antonoriza.com/incremental-disruptive-innovations/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Juan Antonio Oriza Armas</author><guid>https://www.antonoriza.com/incremental-disruptive-innovations/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>The other day while  I was scrolling through my LinkedIn feed I read the following quote:</p>
<div class="details admonition quote open">
        <div class="details-summary admonition-title">
            <i class="icon fas fa-quote-right fa-fw" aria-hidden="true"></i>Quote<i class="details-icon fas fa-angle-right fa-fw" aria-hidden="true"></i>
        </div>
        <div class="details-content">
            <div class="admonition-content"><em>«The electric light did not come from the continuous improvement of candles»</em>
-Oren Harari</div>
        </div>
    </div>
<p>This idea is relevant in the process of creating products and services, specifically it exemplifies the “incremental” versus “disruptive” improvement concepts.</p>
<p>The term “creation” is clear but in the current world a lot of people just copy/duplicate someone else&rsquo;s product/service and implement it in their country or region  targeting it as “innovation”. This is wrong, and what they are merely doing is taking advantage of one of the economic features of globalization.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Why do I have a Blog?</title><link>https://www.antonoriza.com/why-have-blog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Juan Antonio Oriza Armas</author><guid>https://www.antonoriza.com/why-have-blog/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have been curious about starting or not a blog. There are a lot of texts out there that already share good insights and ideas  around different topics of my interest, so why should I repeat the same information?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But the thing is I believe there are a lot of things out there waiting to be told in a fresh and wild way. When you take a different perspective or approach, you may discover insights that others have missed.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>